Perfection is impossible. In the 1,526 singles matches, I played in my career, I won.
Almost 80% of those matches. Now, I have a question for you. What percentage of points do you think
I want in those matches? Only 54% in other words, even top ranked tennis players,
when barely more than half of the points they play. When you lose every second point on average,
you learn not to dwell on every shot. You teach yourself to think, okay, I double fault it,
it's only a point. Okay, I came to the net and I got passed again. It's only a point.
Even a great shot, an overhead back-and-smash that ends up on ESPN's top 10 play list,
that too, is just a point. So here's why I'm telling you this. When you're playing a point,
it has to be the most important thing in the world than it is. But when it's behind you,
it's behind you. This mindset is really crucial because it frees you to fully commit to the next point
at the next point after that. With intensity, clarity and focus.